Hello, I'm Tyler Tiley and today I'm
joined by Mount Hope Mining Managing
Director Fergus Kylie. Fergus, welcome.
Thanks for joining me today.
>> Good day, Tyler. Thanks for having me.
Joining you live in the field from the
top of Mount Solitary.
>> So, you've just locked in an around $1.8
million placement. Can you run us
through the raise and what it means for
Mount Hope?
>> Yeah, look Tyler, this is a a a pivotal
point in the company's history. We were
very fortunate enough to secure the
backing of some of Western Australia's
most prolific gold finders and
discoverers in the ex-Spartan Resources
team led by Simon Lawson, Craig Jones,
and Dave Coyne through their newly
formed fund Ronan Metals. The
opportunity to to present to them
recently and look they they just sort of
could see the opportunity that we had in
front of us. They really
liked the the potential for the rocks
where we're at, the fact that we're in a
proven mining jurisdiction, and of
course the fact that we think or that we
can see that we've got potential
multi-million ounce potential in the MS2
corridor and they were really excited by
that based on on their own history of of
gold discovery albeit in in WA of
course. So, look it was a really natural
synergy. It came together really well.
It was a a non-brokered deal of course.
They cornerstoned the raise with a
little over a million dollars
with the remainder going to our a couple
of our key shareholders and
participation by management. So, a
really great outcome for the company and
really strengthens the balance sheet
going into this next work program.
>> As you said, the placement was led by
Ronan Metals. How important is that
endorsement for the company?
>> Yeah, look I think it's really important
for us, Tyler. It's it's particularly
difficult when you sit as sort of a
small or or microcap explorer promoting
your story. I mean everyone says they've
got great projects and and many of these
companies do, of course. But, for the
broader market, particularly people who
might not be technically driven, when
when much of the story is technically
orientated right now, looking at analogs
to to nearby systems, that sort of
thing, is very helpful to have
third-party endorsement of the project
and of the opportunity, particularly
when that that those third parties
have seen success, plenty of success, in
in the field in which we're operating.
So, you know, not only is it is it a
gratification for the existing
management team and the strategy that
we're executing, having collected our
rocks and pursuing exploration out here,
but I think it's also a really good nod
to the company for the broader investing
community, those that might not have the
technical background as say some of us,
boring old rock lickers who have have
done a little bit of this in the past.
>> You're on site now at Mount Solitary,
where drilling is underway. What's the
focus of this next phase?
>> Yeah, look, that's the other great part
of of today's announcement, Tyler. We're
of course commencing our drill program
today, which is the phase three program.
We know we've had some exceptional drill
results at Mount Solitary today, 6 m at
18 g, 19 m at 4 1/2 g, in the first
couple of programs.
We've also produced some exceptional
metallurgical results, really high
grade recovery of the gold, up to 98% or
98.4%. So, this next program is about
expanding the known mineralized envelope
for Mount Solitary. We're looking to
effectively try and double it along
strike and and down dip. We have a
really compelling
CSAMT target that is sitting almost sort
of 200-ish m south of the mineralized
envelope, which we think is the
potentially the down
plunge and strike extension of of Mount
Solitary, what we're sitting on here.
So, we're going to be drilling this this
project off the edge of this hill that
I'm standing on to the south
and south of all of the old workings
where no one's ever really tested or
drilled it before. Of course, this will
be a test of our of our structural model
and and our geological understanding and
we're really hoping
to hit out in this next program because
then of course, you know, that would be
validation for the for the work that
we've done to date
and would give us the ability to keep
exploring in that in that general
direction and that plunge. Importantly
as well, another aspect of this program
is looking to advance this towards a
maiden JORC MRE. So of course, that
drilling program will contribute heavily
towards towards that outcome for the
company.
>> So what are the key milestones that
investors should be keeping an eye on
for from here?
>> Yeah, look with the strength and balance
sheet of that of the private placement
plus the drilling that we're undertaking
now, we're really going to start ramping
up our exploration activities. Of
course, we've got this drill program
that we're we're kicking off today. And
so there'll be the results from that
program. As I mentioned, we're we're
advancing towards an MRE. So we look
we're hoping to have that completed in
the in the not too distant future. We
knew that we got some exceptional
metallurgical results. So we're looking
to kick off a phase two
metallurgy program which will be
certainly sort of more broad and
holistic than the than the phase one
program. So investors can keep an eye
out on on that. We're commencing our um
permitting activities as we advance the
the the prospect towards a mining
license. The broader backdrop here is
that there's seven different mines and
mills within 200 km of this great
project here. We're 500 m from a bitumen
road just over there. The town of Mount
Hope is is 2 km that way. This is a
perfect location for developing a a new
operation and of course, there's these
hungry mills that are nearby that
they're you know, they provide plenty of
opportunity for us uh provide feeds. So,
look, we're going to really speed up
that activity, particularly with um with
this new investment from Simon Lawson
and the right Ronan guys, uh it's going
to be really about unlocking uh the
multi-million ounce sort of potential
that we can see and trying to bring some
of that to light along this MS2 corridor
um and uh and hopefully bringing
investors along with us on that journey.
>> Fergus, it's been a pleasure. Thanks so
much for your time today.
>> Appreciate it, Tyler. Thank you very
much and uh look forward to keeping
everyone updated as we go.
>> For more ASX news and analysis,
subscribe below.